Hey, hey. What's up, my friend? So, in
today's video, I want to talk about how
to deal with a losing streak. So, follow
along with
me. Have you ever learned a new trading
system, maybe from a book, a blog, a
website, whatsoever, and then you trade
that system, and at the start, you make
some money, right? You had a three,
four, five winning trades in a row. And
then you encounter one losses, two
losses, and before you know it, you're
losing five, six, seven trades in a row.
You're in a losing streak. So, what do
you do? Well, you tell yourself, hm,
maybe the system isn't working anymore.
Let me find another trading system,
something that's
better. And then you find another
trading system and again you get some
winners at the start. And then
eventually you face another losing
streak. Why is
that? So, if you ever feel that way,
don't worry. You're not alone. And this
is why in today's video, you'll discover
why a losing streak occur. You'll learn
how to deal with a losing streak.
And more importantly, I'll also share
with you how you can profit almost every
year, even if you have a losing streak.
Sounds good? Then let's get started. So
the first thing that I want to talk
about
is a trivia with you, right? What does
or what do a winning and losing trading
system have in common? I'll give you
five seconds. One, two, three, four,
five. Okay, the answer is this, right?
When you have a winning or a losing
trading system, right, the one thing
they have common is this. They all have
losing streaks. You can have a
profitable trading system that has made
money over the last 10, 20 years, but
guess what? You will still face losing
streaks from time to time.
Okay? So
before you deal with a losing streak,
right, you might be in a losing streak
right now or you might feel lost, right?
Whenever you're in a losing streak,
before you even want to tackle that
problem, you need to first ask
yourself, does your trading system
works? That's it, right? You must make
sure that the trading system that you
are trading, it has to be a profitable
trading system. It has to be a winning
trading system. It has to be a trading
system that gives you an edge in the
long run. Because if you have a losing
trading system and you are trying to
overcome a losing streak with a losing
trading system, then it's not going to
solve the big problem because you're
just kind of
like treating the symptoms and not the
cost, right? So the first thing that you
want to find out to work with is to make
sure that you have a winning trading
system, a trading system that actually
makes money in the long run. And I think
this is a quote that I love, right? I
saw this on uh Twitter, otherwise known
as X, right? Now, you can't meditate
your way out of a bad trading
system. So, first thing first, before
you deal with a losing streak, make sure
that your trading system has an age
because it's like, you know, you going
down to a casino. You can wear your
favorite lucky underwear. You can blow
the dice before you roll the dice. You
can have all the fancy betting
strategies, but will any of that matter?
And the answer for the most of the
general population is no. None of it
will matter because you don't have an
edge over the house. You don't have an
edge over the casino. And it's the same
as
trading. So, I suspect most of you
watching this video now, you don't have
an edge in the market. So, to make your
life easier to help you find an age, you
can go down to my website over here and
grab a copy of this book called The
Essential Guide to Systems Trading. This
one over here.
Okay? The website's here, tradinger.com,
and download and grab a copy of this
guide. is free. So what's going to
happen is that this guide will teach you
the method that I use to find proven
trading systems that work. This will
also share with you a simple trend
following system that allows you to
profit in bull and bare markets even
during a recession. So you can use the
system as a framework to develop your
own if you wish. So ultimately my hope
is to help you shortcut your learning
curve. So go and grab a copy of this
guide. I'll put the link in the
description. You can so you can grab a
copy. So once you have a trading system
that works and then you're in the losing
streak, then now it's time to apply
techniques to deal with the losing
streak. And the first technique is this.
I want you to ask yourself, is the
trading system performing the way it
should? Because here's the thing, no
trading system works all the time
because guess what? Market conditions
change all the time. One time the market
could be in a rangebound market
condition, then it could be in an
uptrend, then be a reversal in a
downtrend and whatnot. So a trading
system is only meant to profit in a
certain market conditions and since you
know market conditions change no trading
system is going to work all the time
task it is very important to know when
your trading system performs and when it
underperforms. This is very important.
So let me give you an example. So for
let's say a trader who applies a trend
following system in the stock market is
going to make money when the stock
market is in an uptrend.
And likewise, when the stock market is
in a downtrend, a trend follower who is
long only in the stock market will lose
money in a bare market. You will lose
money in a recession or a financial
crisis. So this is important, right, to
know when your trading system is
supposed to perform and when it's not
supposed to perform. So this way you can
manage expectations because what's going
to be interesting is this is that if you
are using a trend following system and
you're on a losing streak because it's a
bare market. Guess what? It is normal.
It is normal. But what's not normal is
that if you are a trend following stock
trader and it's a bare market and you're
making money then something is wrong,
right? It means that you probably are
not following the rules or you know
something is quite off. You should look
into that. So, it's important to know
when you should dig a little bit deeper
and when to know it's just simply the
cost of doing business. And if you ask
me, trading is is this isn't about being
right all the time. You need to know
when you're also supposed to be wrong,
right? Kind of like marriage, right? You
know, when you did something wrong, your
wife is not too happy. You better know
that you are in the wrong. If not, you
won't be sleeping in your comfortable
bed at night. Probably, you know,
somewhere the toilet, balcony,
whatsoever. Okay, so that's the first
thing, right? Ask yourself is it
performing the way that it should.
Second one is this zoom out. So if you
look at this right this is a trading
system
that that uh I teach right called a mean
reversion trading system. And you can
see that since this is 2025 I think you
can't see the date but it's 2025. Since
the start of this year you can see that
this system it's actually losing money.
Okay. A series of lower highs, lower
highs, lower highs, lower highs, lower
highs and lower lows, right? Lower lows,
lower lows, lower lows. Can't even apply
basic technical analysis here. And for
new traders, traders who
are not experienced, they might look at
this man, Raina, look at this equity
curve of this system. It's no longer
working, man. Let
me abandon this system and look for
something better, something that works
in today's market condition. But here's
the thing, right? If you only look at
the results over the last 5 months, four
months, you're going to miss the forest
for the trees. Because if I were to show
you the results, the back test results
over the last 10 over years. You can see
that what's happening now is that you
are just simply in a draw down. The the
downtrend that you saw earlier is pretty
much from this portion only. Okay, this
portion is the downtrend. So you are
actually quitting this trading system at
one of the worst possible times because
if you look at this results
historically it's a matter of time
before this system usually break up to
new alltime high and if you were to
abandon the system at this juncture
what's going to happen what's going to
happen is that the system eventually
does recover and you are on the
sidelines because you gave up on this
system you look for something new alto
together and I can assure you whichever
new trading system that you try you're
going to face losing streaks again and
then this pattern will rinse repeat
itself over and over again. Right? So
this is why it's so important to make
sure that your trading system has an age
in the markets. You understand what it
age is and you understand how it has
performed in the past. So this will
gives you confidence, gives you the data
that you need to know that okay I must
stick to the rules of this trading
system because there's a good chance it
will continue to break up to new
all-time high. It will continue to
perform in the future.
And a very simple quote right relates to
trading. If in doubt, zoom out. So this
can be applied to you know for example
wanting to know to know whether should
you give up on your trading system or
not. If you're in doubt look back right
where are you in the grand scheme of
things. Is this part of the normal draw
down? Okay. Or is this something much
deeper that you are not expecting. So if
in doubt zoom out because usually when
you zoom out you realize oh we have been
through this in the past before. This is
not the worst right? This is pretty much
the normal app and flow of the market.
It's a normal e and flow of the the uh
losses that comes along with this type
of trading system. And of course, this
also applies to discretionary traders,
right? Where if you're on a 1 hour, 5
minutes time frame, you do not know
what's the market likely to do. Just
zoom out to the higher time frame, 4
hour, daily time frame to give you a
clearer picture. But I'm I'm uh getting
sidetracked over here. And finally, last
one,
diversification. So, let me share with
you a story, right? So, I started off as
a trend follower, right? trend follower
to profits in you know when markets is
trending uptrend down trend I will make
money but when the markets are choppy
when it's rangebound as a trend follower
trade and I'm a trend follower back then
was in the futures market trading forex
commodities indices agriculture etc when
the markets are choppy and rangebound as
a trend follow I won't make money I'll
probably you know give up quite a bit of
profits I'll be in the red and what
happened is that I remember right I
can't remember which year was it right
but this particular few years as a trend
follow I wasn't really making much
profit. But people, traders in the stock
market, they are making a killing,
right? Investors who just buy and hold,
they just do nothing and they're making
a buckload of money. Stock traders who
who buy average into their losses, even
though that's usually not the right
thing to do, they are still making even
more money than me, you know, trying to,
you know, profit from trends in the
futures market. And I I was feeling a
little bit upset about it like know here
am I, you know, slugging my slogging my
guts out, you know, trying to capture
trends and not making much. and traders
who are in the stock markets not doing
anything making much more money than me.
So I feel ah so I thought to myself h
would it be nice if I have another
trading system that has exposure to the
stock market. So if the futures market
are not doing
anything I could still make money from
the stock market. So that's where I
develop another trading system for the
stock market called the mean reversion
trading system that looks something like
this. Right? This what you're seeing
over here is the yearly results of this
trading system. So STF is stands for
systematic trend following. MRT stands
for mean reversion trading. And you can
see that both of these trading systems
they all have losing years in between
like trend following is down.7% in 2009.
2023 is down almost 20%. Same for the
mean reversion trading system right two
losing years over here. So we have
losses from time to time.
So where I'm going with this is that
when you have multiple trading system,
what's going to happen is that even if
you have a losing streak, you can
dramatically reduce the number of losing
years that you have. Because right now,
let's say if I combine, let's say, for
example, I have a uh $100,000 trading
capital. I put 50 to systematic trend
following, 50% to mean reversion
trading. What's going to happen is that
I will get this results. This is my net
results. You can see that making money
almost every single year and just had
the one losing year which is 2023. Can
you see from 1, two, three, four losing
years now is being reduced to just one
losing year. So this is the power of
diversification. So if you are a trader
your trading systems and you encounter
losing streaks, guess what? One powerful
way to go about it is to add multiple
uncorrelated trading systems. This will
help you deal better with your losing
streak. you get out of a draw down
faster and you improve your risk
adjusted returns just by having multiple
trading systems. And if you want to
learn more, I wrote a book called
Trading Systems that work. You can grab
a copy. This book will teach you three
proven trading systems that work so you
can profit from the stock market. You
can profit in bull and bare markets even
during a recession. So go to the link
over here. I'll just put the link over
here. This is trading systemsbook.com
over here. Okay? You don't you don't
need to put this /newbook page. I think
just you just put trading
systemsbook.com. I'll put the link in
the description. Grab a copy and it
comes with a 180day money back
guarantee. So, for whatever reason you
don't like the book, right, just email
us and we'll happily refund you in full.
And in this book, I'll give you the
exact trading rules for each of the
trading systems. You can see over here,
right, the rules of the trend following
system, the rules of the mean reversion
trading system, and the rules of this
breakout trading system. I'll share with
you the back tested results, the rules,
and how it looks like on the charts and
much more. So, go and grab a copy. And
with that said, I wish you all good
luck, good trading. I will talk to you
soon.